today we are going to learn about a tool
that every single full stack developer
should be aware of why because it's
going to save you so much time you are
going to want to pay for it even though
it's free the name of this wonderful
tool is Keystone JS and I feel guilty
when I use it because of how cool it is
and how much time it saves me
99.9 of the applications you will build
are going to need an admin panel and
building one by hand takes a lot of time
and it's a very repetitive and boring
job with keystone.js you can generate an
admin panel for your application in less
than 10 lines of code you will also get
authentication a graphql API database
migrations relationships filtering file
upload all that out of the box so let's
take a look at the keystone.js Magic by
building and admin panels for an app
like Twitter to get started with
keystone.js on an empty folder we are
going to install Keystone and typescript
then on that same folder we're going to
create a file called
keystone.ts on that file we have to do
two things first we have to configure
our database and then we have to explain
what kind of data is going to be saved
on it to do that we're going to import
the config function and we are going to
call it with a configuration object of
our database we will tell Keystone that
we are going to use sqlite as our
database and we will write down the
location of the database file on our
file system and now we have to explain
to Keystone what is the shape of the
data we are going to save in our
database that will be done inside the
lists property inside of the
configuration object the reason why it's
called lists is because if we think
about it lists is what admin panels have
a list of users a list of tweets likes
Etc inside of the lists object we will
create a user our user is going to have
two Fields a name and an email
both of these fields are going to be
required and we will set the email to be
unique finally we will make write and
read operations on our users public by
setting access to allow all and that's
it we are now ready to see our admin
panel come okay to start the Keystone
Magic on our packets that Json we are
going to create a Dev script that is
going to run the command Keystone that
after we run NVM run Dev UNC keystone.js
generate a graphql and Prisma schema
create the sqlite database create a
graphql API and generate an admin panel
using next JS all that will be running
on a localhost 3000 which is where we
will find our admin panel as you can see
we will get a dashboard with one model
users when we click on the users we will
go and see the list of our users that is
empty for now as you can see when we
click on create users we find that name
and email fields we wrote in our code
just before we can now add a user and
after we do we are redirected to the
edit user page which was also Auto
generated for us we can also go back to
the users list and see how the user we
created is there as well as the
possibility of searching sorting and
filtering our users by their fields but
that is not all if we go to localhost
3000 slash API graphql we will see a
graphql API Explorer it will have
queries to get one user or all users and
it will have mutations to create delete
and update a single user or all of them
this is absolutely insane how amazing is
this just one typescript file that plus
a little bit of code and Keystone can
generate all that incredible now that we
have the user model we are going to
create the Tweet model so we can learn
how to do relationships and connect
models to each other's own system on our
Keystone that DS file after our user we
will add a tweet model the new tweet
model will have a Content text field
that will be required and will be
between 1 and 140 characters long it
will have a created add field with the
now kind to save the date when a tweet
is created we are also connecting the
user model with the Tweet model using
the relationship function on the user
model we are saying that the user has
tweets and that the user will be found
as the author on the Tweet model we are
also saying that the user can have many
to it and on the Tweet model we are
saying that the Tweet has an author and
that this to it will be found inside of
user dot tweets after we restart our
server we will now see how we have two
models user and tweet when we go and try
to add a tweet we will be able to write
the content of the Tweet we will see a
calendar with it and we can also select
an author for our tweet which will be
the user we selected before after we do
that if we go to our user detail page we
will also see that the user now has a
field for all the tweets connected to it
we can make our admin panel even better
by changing how the tweets look like
right now we can only see their random
IDs to change that we are going to go
back to our config file and there we are
going to customize the UI of our tweets
field on the user model here we are
saying that we want to display the
tweets like cards and that we want to
see the content and created add fields
of the tweets on those cards after we
restart the server and create a new
tweet under the same user if we go to
the edit user page we will see how now
the tweets are displayed in a much much
better more clear way let's not forget
to check out the API Explorer and sure
enough we will find how we now have
queries to read a tweet all tweets and
mutations to create and update them
absolutely fantastic this is not all
keystone.js can do we can also add
authentication to protect our API and
access control to select who can edit
and delete data and we can even extend
the graphql schema to execute whatever
custom code we want to the code towards
authentication would look something like
this first we tell Keystone what is the
model that will hold our users what
identifier will be in this case email
and what the secret field is then the
code to authorize the user looks
something like this where only a user
that has the is admin property on their
session will be allowed to create update
and delete a tweet the code to extend
the graphql schema would look something
like this as you can see we can provide
our own mutations and we can write our
own resolvers there we can talk to the
database directly and that's it for this
video I am super curious to know what
you think about Keystone let me know in
the comments below your opinion is and
if you would like me to make a longer
more detailed tutorial if you found this
video useful please consider liking it
and subscribing to the channel and don't
forget that if you want to learn things
like JavaScript python react react
native gold Dart flutter among many
others for absolutely free all you have
to do is click the link below to join
any of our many free courses that you
can take right now for absolutely free
with me click the link below and I will
see you then
see you on the next one bye
foreign